Samuel CookSystem Administrator

e: sjcook.au@icloud.com w: www.leaylam.com m: +61 476 984 193

Personal Profile

Completion of a Bachelor of Information Technology from USQ by the end of 2018 and planned graduation ceremony in April 2019 as well as additional experience within the information sector prior to study, I would make a suitable candidate for entry to mid level positions.

During my studies at USQ I completed CCNA training that involved hands-on labs, providing knowledge to manage and troubleshoot Cisco routers and switches. Previous industry experience will allow for fast adaption to environments utilising Active Directory, Exchange and Windows Server Environments.

Work Experience

Wireless Systems Engineer at Sitech Construction Systems

January 2014 - March 2015

Working primarily with Rajant wireless mesh technology and the design and implementation of Rajant mesh networks. This included troubleshooting network issues in both ethernet and wireless, analysis of healthy and unhealthy networks to determine optimisation options.

Configuration of 3G/4G gateways for use with Trimble GPS base stations for use on Trimble OmniSTAR network. Review existing servers (Windows Server 2003, 2008 and 2012) and Active Directory and the network and make recommendations.

IT Support Analyst at Glencore Coal Assets Australia

December 2012 - December 2013

My time at Glencore allowed access to varying projects and disciplines within the Mining and IT area from setting up virtual machines to managing cable installations. This position provided me with skills that I have built on and refined.

Some of the regular tasks I performed included managing users and groups with Active Directory and Powershell, SOE deployments using Alitris Deployment Solution (6.9), setup and management of physical and virtual servers (Hyper-V), creating and managing Exchange users and groups, setup and management of network and switches additional to troubleshooting issues with site network (copper and fibre) and phones (POTS and VOIP).

While at Glencore I was part of a rostered on-call service with rotation every 14 weeks and was based between two regional sites, Rolleston Coal and Oaky Creek Coal.

Projects I have been involved with were assisting with the deployment of a wireless mesh network (Tropos) at Rolleston Coal, intitiing NTFS permission changes throughout a site that included meetings with departments to understand ideal file structures. Network installations at site and the management of contractors involved.

Graduate IT Engineer at Xstrata Coal OLD

April 2011 - December 2012

Deployment of SOE, Deployment of software packages, Desktop support, Rostered on call every 7 weeks for Xstrata Coal Queensland, Create new users for site using Active Directory.

Mine Planner at Newlands Coal

June 2008 - April 2011

Running schedules in XPAC and Primavera planning software, Bi-monthly forecast development and longwall production, Producing graphs and diagrams for commercial team used in Joint Venture meetings.

Mine Surveyor at Newlands Coal

November 2007 - June 2008

Responsible for all surveying at mine site, Underground and surface during rostered days on (7/7), Surface setouts with Leica survey equipment, Underground surveying

with Leica survey equipment, Weekly measures of development and longwall, Updating mine plan weekly, Maintaining all statutory mine plans, Responsible for training new graduate surveyor.

Graduate Surveyor at Xstrata Coal

November 2005 - November 2007

Maintaining continuous production in development panels, Surface set-outs with GPS, Underground set-outs with traditional survey methods, Weekly measures of development and longwall, Update mine plan weekly for use throughout site, Update and deliver monthly plans to critical personnel around site.

Student Surveyor at PMM

June 2004 - October 2005

Standard Lot Subdivisions, Measuring up for Leases, Building and Volumetric Format Plans, Cadastral Surveys

Key Skills

Linux (Debian)
JavaScript
HTML & CSS
Bash Scripting
Powershell
Cisco CCNA
Active Directory
AWS CloudFront

AWS S3
AWS Elastic Beanstalk
SQL
VMWare

■ Microsoft Servers

Microsoft Servers Microsoft Azure Microsoft Hyper-V

Education

University of Southern Queensland

BITC (Networking & Security)

Completing at the end of 2018, The USQ Bachelor of Information Technology is an accreddited program by the <u>Australian Computer Society</u>.

Toowoomba Grammar School

High School Certificate

Completed in 2001.